## Jake Lira

Austin, TX 78729 | 310-955-7319 | LLira09@gmail.com Github | LinkedIn | jakelira.com

## **Software Engineer**

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in Graphic Design. Possess strong skills in analytical thinking and problem solving that help technology-driven, innovation focused companies by exceeding expectations and performing duties thoughtfully and efficiently. Demonstrated ability to be resilient and adaptable in a dynamic environment.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Express, Node, Ruby, Rails, SQL, MongoDB

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Fitness Trainer - Github | Demo

A website for users to get weekly/monthly workouts from their coach/trainer

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Created all models for MongoDB which allows storage of Users, Coach profiles and workout records
- Setup controllers and routes which allow users to create profiles
- Created front end components which allow users to intuitively navigate the site

# Mechanical Keyboards - Github | Demo

E-Comm store for mechanical keyboards and mice

- Created product components allowing users to see product details page to facilitate purchase decisions
- Setup components for product rating to show in the front end
- Styled website using react-bootstrap

### Looking For Group - Github |

A website that allows gamers to create a profile, share posts, and get help from other gamers

- Designed forms for creating: users, comments, and posts
- Queried data to display into the front end
- Built back end using Express, Node, and MongoDB

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**AudioEye** Austin, TX 02/2022-Present

Implementation JavaScript Developer - contract

- Implemented individualized accessible remediations to websites using WCAG 2.0 AA using compliant standards.
- Collaborated with the project team throughout product lifecycle to ensure compliance and expected architectures on client websites.
- Worked in Agile development environment(JIRA)

**ThriveDX** Austin, TX Associate Instructor 02/2022-Present

- Tech: JavaScript, Node, React, MongoDB, SQL, Python
- Assist students with troubleshooting and debugging their code
- Fostered a learning environment and mentored students to understand how to create full-stack applications

#### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Austin, TX

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

08/2020 - 12/2020

Cal State University Northridge Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) in Graphic Design Northridge, CA 05/2014